import PRA1 from "./PRA1.mp4"
import PRA2 from "./PRA2.mp4"
import PRA3 from "./PRA3.mp4"
import PRA4 from "./PRA4.mp4"
import PRA5 from "./PRA5.mp4"
import PRA6 from "./PRA6.mp4"
import PRA7 from "./PRA7.mp4"
import PRA8 from "./PRA8.mp4"
import PRA9 from "./PRA9.mp4"
import PRA10 from "./PRA10.mp4"
import PRA11 from "./PRA11.mp4"
import PRA12 from "./PRA12.mp4"
import PRA13 from "./PRA13.mp4"
import PRA14 from "./PRA14.mp4"
import PRA15 from "./PRA15.mp4"
import PRA16 from "./PRA16.mp4"
import PRA17 from "./PRA17.mp4"
import PRA18 from "./PRA18.mp4"
import PRA19 from "./PRA19.mp4"
import PRA20 from "./PRA20.mp4"
import PRA21 from "./PRA21.mp4"
import PRA22 from "./PRA22.mp4"
import PRA23 from "./PRA23.mp4"
import PRA24 from "./PRA24.mp4"
import PRA25 from "./PRA25.mp4"
import PRA26 from "./PRA26.mp4"
import PRA27 from "./PRA27.mp4"
import PRA28 from "./PRA28.mp4"
import PRA29 from "./PRA29.mp4"
import PRA30 from "./PRA30.mp4"
import PRA31 from "./PRA31.mp4"
import PRA32 from "./PRA32.mp4"
import PRA33 from "./PRA33.mp4"
import PRA34 from "./PRA34.mp4"
import PRA35 from "./PRA35.mp4"
import PRA36 from "./PRA36.mp4"
import PRA37 from "./PRA37.mp4"
import PRA38 from "./PRA38.mp4"
import PRA39 from "./PRA39.mp4"
import PRA40 from "./PRA40.mp4"
import PRA41 from "./PRA41.mp4"
import PRA42 from "./PRA42.mp4"
import PRA43 from "./PRA43.mp4"
import PRA44 from "./PRA44.mp4"
import PRA45 from "./PRA45.mp4"
import PRA46 from "./PRA46.mp4"
import PRA47 from "./PRA47.mp4"
import PRA48 from "./PRA48.mp4"
import PRA49 from "./PRA49.mp4"
import PRA50 from "./PRA50.mp4"
import PRA51 from "./PRA51.mp4"
import PRA52 from "./PRA52.mp4"
import PRA53 from "./PRA53.mp4"
import PRA54 from "./PRA54.mp4"
import PRA55 from "./PRA55.mp4"
import PRA56 from "./PRA56.mp4"
import PRA57 from "./PRA57.mp4"
import PRA58 from "./PRA58.mp4"
import PRA59 from "./PRA59.mp4"
import PRA60 from "./PRA60.mp4"
import PRA61 from "./PRA61.mp4"
import PRA62 from "./PRA62.mp4"
import PRA63 from "./PRA63.mp4"
import PRA64 from "./PRA64.mp4"
import PRA65 from "./PRA65.mp4"
import PRA66 from "./PRA66.mp4"
import PRA67 from "./PRA67.mp4"
import PRA68 from "./PRA68.mp4"
import PRA69 from "./PRA69.mp4"
import PRA70 from "./PRA70.mp4"
import PRA71 from "./PRA71.mp4"
import PRA72 from "./PRA72.mp4"
import PRA73 from "./PRA73.mp4"
import PRA74 from "./PRA74.mp4"
import PRA75 from "./PRA75.mp4"
import PRA76 from "./PRA76.mp4"
import PRA77 from "./PRA77.mp4"
import PRA78 from "./PRA78.mp4"
import PRA79 from "./PRA79.mp4"
import PRA80 from "./PRA80.mp4"
import PRA81 from "./PRA81.mp4"
import PRA82 from "./PRA82.mp4"
import PRA83 from "./PRA83.mp4"
import PRA84 from "./PRA84.mp4"
import PRA85 from "./PRA85.mp4"
import PRA86 from "./PRA86.mp4"
import PRA87 from "./PRA87.mp4"
import PRA88 from "./PRA88.mp4"
import PRA89 from "./PRA89.mp4"
import PRA90 from "./PRA90.mp4"
import PRA91 from "./PRA91.mp4"
import PRA92 from "./PRA92.mp4"
import PRA93 from "./PRA93.mp4"
import PRA94 from "./PRA94.mp4"
import PRA95 from "./PRA95.mp4"
import PRA96 from "./PRA96.mp4"
import PRA97 from "./PRA97.mp4"
import PRA98 from "./PRA98.mp4"





export const pradaDev = [
    {
        id: 869,
        videoFile: PRA98,
        rusQuestion: "дополнительная работа",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a situation in which someone expects another person to do something that they do not want to do or that is not convenient: ",
        answer: "imposition",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 868,
        videoFile: PRA97,
        rusQuestion: "вспышка",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a small spot of light, sometimes with a short, sharp sound, that appears on a computer screen",
        answer: "blip",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 867,
        videoFile: PRA96,
        rusQuestion: "воспитывать",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to take care of, feed, and protect someone or something, especially young children or plants, and help him, her, or it to develop:",
        answer: "nurture",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 866,
        videoFile: PRA95,
        rusQuestion: "предприятие",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "an organization, especially a business, or a difficult and important plan, especially one that will earn money:",
        answer: "enterprise",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 865,
        videoFile: PRA94,
        rusQuestion: "благодать",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "approval or kindness, especially (in the Christian religion) that is freely given by God to all humans:",
        answer: "grace",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 864,
        videoFile: PRA93,
        rusQuestion: "ослабленный",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "damaged in a way that makes something less effective:",
        answer: "impaired",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 863,
        videoFile: PRA92,
        rusQuestion: "с широко раскрытыми глазами",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "too willing to believe and admire what you see or are told: ",
        answer: "wide-eyed",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 862,
        videoFile: PRA91,
        rusQuestion: "серьезный",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "serious and determined, especially too serious and unable to find your own actions funny:",
        answer: "earnest",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 861,
        videoFile: PRA90,
        rusQuestion: "печально известный",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "famous for something bad: ",
        answer: "notorious",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 860,
        videoFile: PRA89,
        rusQuestion: "аромат",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a sweet or pleasant smell: ",
        answer: "fragrance",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 859,
        videoFile: PRA88,
        rusQuestion: "всплеск",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "If a liquid splashes or if you splash a liquid, it falls on or hits something or someone: ",
        answer: "splash",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 858,
        videoFile: PRA87,
        rusQuestion: "ледник",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a large mass of ice that moves slowly",
        answer: "glacier",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 857,
        videoFile: PRA86,
        rusQuestion: "привратник",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "someone who has the power to decide who gets particular resources and opportunities, and who does not :",
        answer: "gatekeeper",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 856,
        videoFile: PRA85,
        rusQuestion: "признаться",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to admit that you have done something wrong:",
        answer: "own up",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 855,
        videoFile: PRA84,
        rusQuestion: "корпус мира",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "an organization in the US that sends people to work as volunteers (= people who work without being paid) in poor countries",
        answer: "the peace corps",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 854,
        videoFile: PRA83,
        rusQuestion: "скидка , снижение",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "the act of making something, or of something becoming, smaller in size, amount, degree, importance, etc.: ",
        answer: "reduction",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 853,
        videoFile: PRA82,
        rusQuestion: "честность , целостность",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "the quality of being honest and having strong moral principles that you refuse to change: ",
        answer: "integrity",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 852,
        videoFile: PRA81,
        rusQuestion: "кочерга",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a long, thin metal stick that you use to move around coal or wood in a fire so that it burns better",
        answer: "poker",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 851,
        videoFile: PRA80,
        rusQuestion: "очевидно",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "in a way that is easy to see: ",
        answer: "evidently",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 850,
        videoFile: PRA79,
        rusQuestion: "ерзать",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to make continuous, small movements, especially if they do not have a particular purpose and you make them without meaning to, for example because you are nervous or bored:",
        answer: "fidget",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 849,
        videoFile: PRA78,
        rusQuestion: "слабый",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to suddenly become unconscious for a short time, usually falling down:",
        answer: "faint",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 848,
        videoFile: PRA77,
        rusQuestion: "подготовка",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "the actions involved in preparing something, especially food, or the time taken to prepare it: ",
        answer: "prep",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 847,
        videoFile: PRA76,
        rusQuestion: "кулон",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a piece of jewellery worn around the neck, consisting of a long chain with an object hanging from it, or the object itself: ",
        answer: "pendant",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 846,
        videoFile: PRA75,
        rusQuestion: "браслет",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a ring of stiff plastic, metal, etc. worn around the wrist or arm as jewellery",
        answer: "bangle",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 845,
        videoFile: PRA74,
        rusQuestion: "черновик",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a piece of text, a formal suggestion, or a drawing in its original state, often containing the main ideas and intentions but not the developed form:",
        answer: "draft",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 844,
        videoFile: PRA73,
        rusQuestion: "регулировать",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to change something slightly, especially to make it more correct, effective, or suitable: ",
        answer: "adjust",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 843,
        videoFile: PRA72,
        rusQuestion: "возводить",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to build a building, wall, or other structure: ",
        answer: "erect",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 842,
        videoFile: PRA71,
        rusQuestion: "тротуар",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a path with a hard surface on one or both sides of a road, that people walk on: ",
        answer: "pavement",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 841,
        videoFile: PRA70,
        rusQuestion: "фойе",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a large open area just inside the entrance of a public building such as a theatre or a hotel, where people can wait and meet each other: ",
        answer: "foyer",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 840,
        videoFile: PRA69,
        rusQuestion: "предельное",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "used to emphasize how important or serious something is: ",
        answer: "utmost",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 839,
        videoFile: PRA68,
        rusQuestion: "потрясен",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "having strong feelings of shock or disapproval:",
        answer: "appalled",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 838,
        videoFile: PRA67,
        rusQuestion: "морщиться",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to bring your lips tightly together so that they form a rounded shape, usually as an expression of disapproval:",
        answer: "purse",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 837,
        videoFile: PRA66,
        rusQuestion: "болтать",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to talk continuously and eagerly, especially about things that are not important: ",
        answer: "gab",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 836,
        videoFile: PRA65,
        rusQuestion: "пончо",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a piece of clothing made of a single piece of material, with a hole in the middle through which you put your head",
        answer: "poncho",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 835,
        videoFile: PRA64,
        rusQuestion: "иконография",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "the use of images and symbols to represent ideas, or the particular images and symbols used in this way by a religious or political group, etc.: ",
        answer: "iconography",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 834,
        videoFile: PRA63,
        rusQuestion: "полезность",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a service that is used by the public, such as an electricity or gas supply: ",
        answer: "utility",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 833,
        videoFile: PRA62,
        rusQuestion: "повязка на голову",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a narrow strip of material worn around the head, usually to keep your hair or sweat out of your eyes, for example when doing sports: ",
        answer: "headband",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 832,
        videoFile: PRA61,
        rusQuestion: "боль в сердце",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "feelings of great sadness: ",
        answer: "heartache",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 831,
        videoFile: PRA60,
        rusQuestion: "крайний , полный",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "complete or extreme: ",
        answer: "utter",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 830,
        videoFile: PRA59,
        rusQuestion: "ресница",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "any of the short hairs that grow along the edges of the eye: ",
        answer: "eyelash",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 829,
        videoFile: PRA58,
        rusQuestion: "непризнанный",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "not accepted, admitted, or recognized:",
        answer: "unacknowledged",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 828,
        videoFile: PRA57,
        rusQuestion: "трудовая этика",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "the belief that work is morally good:",
        answer: "work ethic",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 827,
        videoFile: PRA56,
        rusQuestion: "воздушный транспорт",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "an operation organized to move supplies or people by aircraft to or from a place that is difficult to reach because of war, a flood, etc",
        answer: "airlift",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 826,
        videoFile: PRA55,
        rusQuestion: "морось",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "rain in very small, light drops:",
        answer: "drizzle",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 825,
        videoFile: PRA54,
        rusQuestion: "шлепающие",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a type of open shoe, often made of rubber, with a V-shaped strap that goes between the big toe and the toe next to it",
        answer: "flip-flop",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 824,
        videoFile: PRA53,
        rusQuestion: "весенние каникулы",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a school holiday in the spring",
        answer: "spring break",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 823,
        videoFile: PRA52,
        rusQuestion: "Дамское белье",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "women's underwear",
        answer: "lingerie",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 822,
        videoFile: PRA51,
        rusQuestion: "торчать",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to continue to do something to its end: ",
        answer: "stick out",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 821,
        videoFile: PRA50,
        rusQuestion: "переснимать",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to record part of a film again, usually in a different way: ",
        answer: "reshoot",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 820,
        videoFile: PRA49,
        rusQuestion: "мельчайшие детали",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "extremely small: ",
        answer: "minute",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 819,
        videoFile: PRA48,
        rusQuestion: "туфли на шпильке",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a shoe with a narrow, high heel, usually worn by women:",
        answer: "stiletto",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 818,
        videoFile: PRA47,
        rusQuestion: "освобождать",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to excuse someone or something from a duty, payment, etc.: ",
        answer: "exempt",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 817,
        videoFile: PRA46,
        rusQuestion: "распродажа",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "an occasion when goods are offered for sale cheaply so that people will be encouraged to buy them and there will be space for new goods:",
        answer: "clearance",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 816,
        videoFile: PRA45,
        rusQuestion: "повседневный",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "oooo clothes are not formal or not suitable for special occasions: ",
        answer: "casual",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 815,
        videoFile: PRA44,
        rusQuestion: "просачивание вниз",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "used to refer to a situation in which something that starts in the high parts of a system spreads to the whole of the system: ",
        answer: "trickle-down",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 814,
        videoFile: PRA43,
        rusQuestion: "универмаг",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a large shop divided into several different parts, each of which sells different things",
        answer: "department store",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 813,
        videoFile: PRA42,
        rusQuestion: "лазурный",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "deep blue in colour",
        answer: "cerulean",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 812,
        videoFile: PRA41,
        rusQuestion: "бирюзовый",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a bluish-green semi-precious stone that is often used in jewellery",
        answer: "turquoise",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 811,
        videoFile: PRA40,
        rusQuestion: "беспечно",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "happily and without feeling or showing any worry, especially when there is a reason to be worried: ",
        answer: "blithely",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 810,
        videoFile: PRA39,
        rusQuestion: "кусок",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a piece of a solid substance, usually with no particular shape: ",
        answer: "lumpy",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 809,
        videoFile: PRA38,
        rusQuestion: "сбивающий с толку",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "impossible for someone to understand or explain: ",
        answer: "baffling",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 808,
        videoFile: PRA37,
        rusQuestion: "талия",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "the part of the body above and slightly narrower than the hips:",
        answer: "waist",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 807,
        videoFile: PRA36,
        rusQuestion: "смесь",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a mixture of different things or styles: ",
        answer: "blend",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 806,
        videoFile: PRA35,
        rusQuestion: "целлюлит",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "ggfat in the human body, especially in the upper legs, that makes the surface of the skin appear lumpy (= not smoothg",
        answer: "cellulite",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 805,
        videoFile: PRA34,
        rusQuestion: "похлебка",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a type of thick soup usually made from fish or other sea creatures: ",
        answer: "chowder",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 804,
        videoFile: PRA33,
        rusQuestion: "туалет",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "informal for toilet: ",
        answer: "loo",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 803,
        videoFile: PRA32,
        rusQuestion: "просматривать",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "If you ooooo something, you practice it or talk about it so the person will know it better:",
        answer: "run through",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 802,
        videoFile: PRA31,
        rusQuestion: "лопаться",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to break open or apart suddenly, or to make something do this: ",
        answer: "burst",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 801,
        videoFile: PRA30,
        rusQuestion: "укомплектование персоналом",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "the process of providing people to do a job, or the number of people who are available to do a job: ",
        answer: "manning",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 800,
        videoFile: PRA29,
        rusQuestion: "шарф",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a strip, square, or triangle of cloth, worn around the neck, head, or shoulders to keep you warm or to make you look attractive: ",
        answer: "scarf",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 799,
        videoFile: PRA28,
        rusQuestion: "конвенция , соглашение ",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a large formal meeting of people who do a particular job or have a similar interest, or a large meeting for a political party: ",
        answer: "convention",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 798,
        videoFile: PRA27,
        rusQuestion: "ранец , сумка",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a rectangular leather bag with a long strap, used especially in the past by children for carrying books to school",
        answer: "satchel",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 797,
        videoFile: PRA26,
        rusQuestion: "пирс , причал",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a long structure sticking out from the land over the sea, where people can walk or large boats can be tied, sometimes with restaurants and places of entertainment on it",
        answer: "pier",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 796,
        videoFile: PRA25,
        rusQuestion: "макет",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to make a model of something in order to show people what it will look like or how it will work",
        answer: "mock up",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 795,
        videoFile: PRA24,
        rusQuestion: "поручение ,",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a short trip you make to do something, such as buying or delivering things in the neighborhood: ",
        answer: "errand",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 794,
        videoFile: PRA23,
        rusQuestion: "швырять ,бросать",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to throw something or someone suddenly and with a lot of force:",
        answer: "fling",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 793,
        videoFile: PRA22,
        rusQuestion: "обжигающий",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "If something, such as a feeling or temperature, is described as ooooo, it is extreme:",
        answer: "searing",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 792,
        videoFile: PRA21,
        rusQuestion: "капанье",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "If a liquid drips, it falls in drops, or you make it fall in drops: ",
        answer: "drip",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 791,
        videoFile: PRA20,
        rusQuestion: "глоток спиртного",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a small amount of a non-alcoholic/alcoholic  drink with a strong taste or effect: ",
        answer: "shot",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 790,
        videoFile: PRA19,
        rusQuestion: "обезжиренное",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "milk from which the cream has been removed",
        answer: "skimmed",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 789,
        videoFile: PRA18,
        rusQuestion: "самородок",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a small roughly shaped piece, especially of gold",
        answer: "nugget",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 788,
        videoFile: PRA17,
        rusQuestion: "ряд",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a number of similar or related events or things, one following another: ",
        answer: "series",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 787,
        videoFile: PRA16,
        rusQuestion: "неадекватный",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "not good enough or too low in quality: ",
        answer: "inadequate",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 786,
        videoFile: PRA15,
        rusQuestion: "стройный",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "thin and delicate, often in a way that is attractive: ",
        answer: "slender",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 785,
        videoFile: PRA14,
        rusQuestion: "особенность , черта",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a typical quality or an important part of something: ",
        answer: "feature",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 784,
        videoFile: PRA13,
        rusQuestion: "парашютист-десантник",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a soldier trained to be dropped from an aircraft with a parachute:",
        answer: "paratrooper",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 783,
        videoFile: PRA12,
        rusQuestion: "компот",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a sweet dish made of cooked fruit",
        answer: "compote",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 782,
        videoFile: PRA11,
        rusQuestion: "ревень",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a plant that has long, sour-tasting red and green stems that can be cooked and eaten as a fruit:",
        answer: "rhubarb",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 781,
        videoFile: PRA10,
        rusQuestion: "дакуаз",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a dessert made from layers of meringue containing ground nuts, with fillings such as cream, ",
        answer: "dacquoise",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 780,
        videoFile: PRA9,
        rusQuestion: "пузатый",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "(especially of a man) having a fat stomach:",
        answer: "paunchy",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 779,
        videoFile: PRA8,
        rusQuestion: "макет",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "the way that something is arranged:",
        answer: "layout",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 778,
        videoFile: PRA7,
        rusQuestion: "поясница",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "the part of the body that is above the legs and below the waist, especially the sexual organs: ",
        answer: "loins",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 777,
        videoFile: PRA6,
        rusQuestion: "препоясывать",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to tie something around your body or part of your body:",
        answer: "gird",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 776,
        videoFile: PRA5,
        rusQuestion: "разрыв",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to (cause something to) explode, break, or tear:",
        answer: "rupture",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 775,
        videoFile: PRA4,
        rusQuestion: "специалист по уходу за лицом",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a person who gives facials and other beauty treatments for the face.",
        answer: "facialist",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 774,
        videoFile: PRA3,
        rusQuestion: "Главный редактор",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "a commander in charge of all the armed forces of a country or of all the forces fighting in a particular area or operation",
        answer: "editor in chief",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 773,
        videoFile: PRA2,
        rusQuestion: "мешок",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to remove someone from a job, usually because they have done something wrong or badly, or sometimes as a way of saving the cost of employing them: ",
        answer: "sack",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "rgb(43, 198, 226)",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
    {
        id: 772,
        videoFile: PRA1,
        rusQuestion: "пленять",
        before: false,
        border: false,
        engDescription: "to hold the attention of someone by being extremely interesting, exciting, pleasant, or attractive: ",
        answer: "captivate",
        myAnswer: "",
        color: "gray",
        getIdx: 1,
        timeGo: 4000,
        try: 1,
        getHight: 1
    },
]